《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
[谁是蝉]
他的匕首消除了我们的超能力
That dagger he had negated our powers.
我失去速度了
I just lost my speed.
我得修正这一切  格蕾西
I'm gonna make this right, Gracie.
每个超能力者都得死
Every meta will die.
所以我们要对付有超能力的开膛手杰克
So we're dealing with a meta-human Jack the Ripper.
他就是奥林·德怀尔  同样也是...
I give you Orlin Dwyer, also known as...
蝉
Cicada.
你拍了多少张了
How many you shoot?
大概一百张吧
Shot like a hundred.
有拍得好的吗
Any of them good?
不知道
Bof.
我想我们要一直拍到弄好为止
Guess we'll just have to keep shooting till we get it right.
我想也是
I guess so.
奥林·德怀尔
Orlin Dwyer.
我们能知道的是  他在中西部长大
Near as we can tell, he grew up in the Midwest.
经常进少管所  踪影无迹可寻
In and out of juvie, pretty much fell off the map,
然后几年前突然出现在中城
and then popped up in Central City a few years ago.
过去的两年里
Part-time employee of Szrek Chemicals
在斯雷克化工厂当临时工
for the last two years.
工头说他不与人来往
Foreman says he keeps to himself,
几乎是个孤家寡人  给了个假住址
pretty much a loner, gave a fake address.
抚养了他的侄女
Did take custody of his niece.
格蕾丝·吉本斯
Grace Gibbons.
她的父母不幸被一个超能力者
After her parents were unfortunately murdered
谋杀后  现在...
by a meta-human, now--
所以我们现在知道了为什么德怀尔恨超能力者
So now we know why Dwyer hates metas.
他一得到超能力就开始攻击他们了
Once he got his powers, he started targeting them.
他在大悟之道那一夜得到了超能力
Powers he got the night of the Enlightenment,
正如我们所知  他被一个
as we all know, and he was struck
尖端科研实验室卫星爆炸产生的碎片击中了
by a shard from the S.T.A.R. Lab satellite explosion.
也是在那一夜
Which was also the same night
格蕾丝陷入了昏迷
that Grace went into a coma.
德怀尔每天每夜都去那里看望她
Where Dwyer visits her every day, every night,
已经三个星期了
for the last three weeks.
所以他正在那里
So he's there now.
-是的  -是的
- Yeah. - Oui.
那我们就去抓他吧
Then let's go get him.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第八集
"我们去抓他吧"
"Let's go get him."
你打算怎么做  听着  和往常一样
How are you going to do that? Look, as always,
我尊重你的精神  巴里·艾伦
I respect your spirit, Barry Allen,
但是只要蝉还有匕首来抑制你的超能力
but as long as Cicada has his dagger to dampen your powers,
就没法阻止他
there's no stopping him.
所以我们来毁掉他的匕首
So let's destroy his dagger.
我们要怎么做呢
How are we gonna do that
除非我们有某种
unless we have some kind of
抑制能力的匕首超能力抑制器
power-dampening dagger power dampener
藏在仓库里呢
hidden away in storage?
我们没有  但如果我们有
We don't, but if we did
我们会想出一个更好的名字来称呼它的
we'd come up with a much better way of saying that.
当然了  就像  匕首抑制器...
Sure, I mean, just, like, dagger-dampener...
等等  那个其实还不错
Wait, yeah, that's actually-- that's decent,
因为你要碰到...
'cause, you know, you're running into...
只要缩写就好了  PDPD.
Just abbreviate. P-D-P-D.
各位
Guys.
要是我们能做一个呢
What if we could make one?
做一个什么
Make one what?
要是我们能做一个比他的武器更强的武器呢
What if we can make a weapon more powerful than his weapon?
蝉可以控制他的匕首
Cicada can control his dagger,
所以我们需要的是比他与匕首的联系更强的
so what we would need would be something more powerful
某个东西
than his connection to it.
-等等  就像某种超负荷磁铁吗  -没错
- Wait, like-- like some kind of super-charged magnet? - Exactly.
我不知道我们有没有足够强的东西来做武器
I don't know if we have anything strong enough for that.
我们用微复合合金做出了萨利
We made Sally out of a micro-composite alloy.
就卫星而言  她...
As far as satellite's go, she's--
她很重
she was heavy-duty.
而且即使我们可以拿到匕首
And even if we could get our hands on the dagger,
我们还要想办法怎么把暗物质取出来
we'd still have to figure out how to take the dark matter out
-才能消除它的超能力  -确实如此
-to negate it's powers. - Well, exactly right.
你的意思我们找到一种合金
I mean, what you're suggesting is we find an alloy--
不是  是无坚不摧的超磁特性合金
No, no, indestructible alloy that has super magnetic properties,
而且同时拥有抵消暗物质的能力
but also has the ability to negate dark matter.
我们要去哪找这种东西
I mean, where are we going to find such a thing?
过去
The past.
The past?
你们已经遇到过我们所需的一切了不是吗
You've already come across everything that we need, right?
超磁特性的强力合金
A strong alloy with magnetic properties.
萨维塔的战衣
Savitar's suit.
能移除暗物质的东西
Something to remove dark matter.
极速用来窃取巴里速度的
The Speed Force transmitter
神速力发射器
that Zoom used to steal Barry's speed.
但那是他的神速力
Yeah, but that was his Speed Force.
没错  但这些都是奇异粒子
Yeah, but those are exotic particles,
与暗能量是同一种物质
which are basically the same thing as dark energy,
所以我们只需要一些来重新做调试就行了
so we would just need some of that to recalibrate it.
你们可以这么做吗
Can-- can you do that?
但必须要给发射器
I mean, you'd have to infuse the transmitter
注入同样的暗物质
with the same kind of dark matter.
类似迪沃那样的吗
Like the DeVoe kind?
是粒子加速器的那种
More like the Particle Accelerator kind.
抱歉  我们又要再炸一次尖端科研实验室吗
I'm sorry, we-- we need to blow up S.T.A.R. Labs again?
不  不是再炸一次
No, no, not again.
我们只要回到粒子加速器第一次爆炸的时候
We just need to go back to the first time that it happened,
这样会把时间线搞得一塌糊涂的
This is gonna mess with the timeline too much.
不会的  萨维塔的战衣  发射器
No, it's not. Savitar's suit, the transmitter,
这些都是在时间线上废弃掉的物品
these are all just discarded objects in time,
所以如果我们拿来用  根本就不会有影响
so if we steal them, it won't affect anything at all.
就算所有计划都成功了
Even if all of that worked,
我们也不能拿着即将命名的抑制装置
we can't just waltz into the hospital
大摇大摆地走进医院
with our soon-to-be-named dampening device.
德怀尔一察觉到我们  他会逃走的
Dwyer smells us coming, he's gone.
那我们来一次时间入侵
Then we do a time hack.
时间入侵
A time hack?
-就是当你...  -在过去放置一件东西
- Is when you-- - Plant something in the past
未来就能找得到
so it's available in the future.
你回到过去  拿走装置
You go back, you take the device,
把它藏在医院附近
and you hide it near the hospital.
五年都没人会找到的地方
Somewhere it won't be found for five years.
他甚至不知道东西在那里
He won't even know it's there.
所以你和你父亲回到过去
So you and your father go back to the past
为了在未来打败蝉
to defeat Cicada in the future.
你想了一个如此随意的计划
Quite an off-the-cuff plan you've come up with.
我们可以的
We can do this.
不行
No.
我一个人去
I can do it.
你们能查查哪天最合适回去吗
Can you guys figure out the best dates to go back to?
马上去查
We're on it.
-你不能跟我一起去  -为什么
- You're not coming with me. - Why?
每次我做这种事都差点没命
Every time I try something like this I nearly get killed.
所以我更要和你一起去
Well, yeah, all the more reason for me to come with you,
这样我就能保护你  你就不会受伤了
so that I can watch your back so you don't get hurt.
时间线太危险了
It's too risky with the timeline.
时间旅行很复杂
All right, look, time travel, it's complicated.
我知道  我已经做过了
I know, I've already done it.
看看弄成什么样了
And look what happened.
听着
Look.
我只想弥补我捅出的篓子
I just want to fix what I screwed up.
为我的行为负责
Okay, what I did.
拜托让我跟你一起去吧
Please, let me come with you.
今天不行
Not today.
你认为她应该跟我一起去
You think she should come with me?
巴里  我认为是的
Yeah, Barry, I do.
爱瑞丝  如果我这么做
Iris, if I do this,
我就要回到那些混乱不安的时期
I'm going back to some crazy times.
萨维塔  极速  斯旺和极速者
Savitar, Zoom, Thawne, Speedsters--
那些你已经战胜打败过的对手
Who you've all outsmarted and defeated.
这是她想出的办法  巴里  她的解决方案
Look, this was her idea, Barry. Her solution.
的确是个好办法
And it's a good one.
除非你有更好的理由
So, unless you have a better reason
她为什么不应该参与
why she should stay back...
让她去吧
let her do this.
好吧  那些是最好的时间点
Okay, these are the best of times.
同时  那些也是最糟的时间点
Incidentally, they were also the worst of times,
但要就回到过去而言  就是它了
but in terms of going back, this is it.
萨维塔  当我们打败他时
Savitar. When we defeated him,
巴里穿进了他的战衣  摧毁了它
Barry phased into his suit, destroyed it,
其中的碎片如果飞得够远
sending pieces of it flying far enough away
过去的我们就不会注意到
that our past selves wouldn't notice
巴里拿走了其中一两片
if Barry took one or two pieces of it.
-你怎么想  -绝对的
- What do you think? - Absolutely,
巴里只需要在时间线追上来之前
Barry just has to get back into the Speed Force
回到神速力中
before the timeline catches up
那些碎片就会从来没出现过
and those pieces get erased from existence.
我还是挺乐观的
I'm fairly optimistic.
好吧  那么那个神速力发射器呢
Okay, what about the Speed Force transmitter thingy?
极速在将神速力注入自己那晚
The night that Zoom injected the speed force into himself,
他将神速力发射器留在了观察室
he left the Speed Force transmitter in the viewing room.
对  真太聪明了  他要做的
Yes, that's brilliant, all he has to do
就是确保在拿走的时候没人看到
is make sure no one's in there when he takes it.
那粒子加速器爆炸那时候呢
What about when the Particle Accelerator exploded?
就是在所有一切都变糟之前
Well, right before everything went sideways,
威尔斯在表层  我们在...
Wells was in the cortex, and we...
我们在管道入口
We were in the pipeline intake.
罗尼
Ronnie!
那是巴里进入时间穹顶的最好时机
That's the best time for Barry to go into the time vault.
他可以把萨维塔战衣的碎片放到底座上
He can put a piece of Savitar's suit in the plinth,
然后当粒子加速器爆炸时
and when the Particle Accelerator explodes
就会给它注入暗物质
it should infuse it with dark matter.
对
Right.
所以这个完成后
So once that's done,
我们就有做装置的所有零件了
we'll have all the pieces we need to make the device.
我们把它放到医院里  剩下的就是历史了
We plant it in the hospital, the rest is history.
很好  咱们去告诉巴里  看他怎么想
Great, let's go show Barry and see what he thinks.
我等下去找你们
I'll be right behind you.
我是放哪里了...
Where did I leave...
这是什么
What is this?
这什么  诺拉的日记吗
What is that? Nora's journal?
怎么  你现在开始偷东西了
What, are you stealing now?
不  是  我有正当理由
No-- yes, but for good reason.
看看这代码
Look at this code.
你之前见过这种代码吗
Have you seen this code before?
-有啊  -有  什么时候
- Yeah. - Yeah, when?
一年前巴里从神速力里出来之后
Right after Barry came out of the Speed Force a year ago.
你破解这代码了吗
And did you decipher the code?
我的电脑只解出了一句话
Well, my computer did just one sentence.
听好了  入侵私人空间侠
Listen here, space invader.
你为什么不试着把这个还给她
Why don't you try returning the thing to her,
然后直接问她
and then asking her?
当然  当然
Of course. Of course.
-对  -有道理
- Right. - Makes sense.
把这个还...
Just return the--
好吧
All right,
咱们开始吧
let's do it.
酷
Cool.
你可别忘了这个
You're not gonna want to forget this.
不得不对战衣做了些调整
Had make some adjustment to the suit,
但我终于搞明白了
but I finally figured it out.
只可用于紧急情况
For emergencies only.
可不能让过去的人看到你
You don't want to get caught running around the past
-穿着未来闪电侠战衣跑来跑去  -是啊
- in your future Flash suit. - Right.
你可能会被启发
You might get ideas.
-谢谢你  -不用谢
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
来吧
Come on.
好了  听我的指令
Okay, look, follow my lead.
别做计划外的事
Don't go off book.
如果有什么出错了  照我说的做
If anything goes wrong, do exactly as I say.
事情一般会出错吗
Do things usually go wrong?
怎么了
What?
我哪还有机会干这事
When am I gonna get the chance to do that?
认真起来
Game face.
他们去时间旅行的时候我们要做什么
All right, so what do we do while they're gone?
去医院盯梢吗
Do we stake out the hospital?
把一切准备好  还是怎么样
Get everything ready here or what?
什么都不做  他们将会在
Nothing. They're gonna return
离开的同一个时间点回来
to the exact same moment that they left.
等等  他们去时间旅行
Wait, so, they're gonna go,
但对于我们来说就像他们从没离开过吗
but to us it'll be like they never left?
没错  时间旅行很怪异  是吧
Yeah, time travel's weird, isn't it?
他们开始了
Here they go.
好运
Good luck.
准备好
Get ready.
就是现在
Now!
你确定我们在正确的位置吗
Are you sure we're in the right place?
那是萨维塔吗
Is that Savitar?
就是他
That's him.
我们走
Come on.
我只剩几分钟了
I only have a few minutes left.
如果我要死
If I am going to die,
那你所爱的一切也都要去死
then everything you love is going to die too.
我的天
Holy shrap.
离飞升只一步之遥却落得如此下场
How's it feel to get so close to your ascension,
这感觉如何
and end up on the ground?
现在我明白了
Now I see.
-这都是注定的  -没有什么是注定的
- It's written. - Nothing's written.
那是什么
What was that?
时间亡灵  他们保护时间线
Time Wraith. They protect the timeline.
我得把时间亡灵引开
I've got to get it out of here.
诺拉  你得弄到碎片  好吗
Nora, you're gonna have to get the shard, okay?
在我们到刚来时的森林处碰头
Meet me in the forest where we first arrived.
妈妈
Mom?
-你拿到了吗  -拿到了
- Did you get it? - Yeah, I got it.
及时把碎片带进神速力  干得漂亮
Nice job getting that into the Speed Force on time.
没什么大不了
Nothing to it.
爸  关于萨维塔
Dad, about Savitar--
没错  这是2016年
This is right. 2016.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
那是极速和沃利
Because that was Zoom with Wally.
我就快失去神速了  跟我来
I'm about to lose my speed. Come on.
-巴里  你没事吧  -我没事
- Barry, are you okay? - I'm okay.
我没事
I'm okay.
谢了  闪电侠
Thank you, Flash.
杰伊  住手
Jay, stop!
如果你还有一点人性尚存
If you have any humanity left,
那求求你  放了他
then please let him go.
凯特琳
Caitlin!
我们得把凯特琳救回来
We gotta get Caitlin back.
待在这  别动
Stay here. Don't move.
好吗  待在这
Okay? Stay.
不
No.
怎么回事
What?
巴里
Barry...
你不能被失败所阻挡
You can't let your losses stop you.
这是你教会我的
You're the one who taught me that.
你得继续向前
You have to keep moving.
你得再努把力
You have to... push through.
你得找到办法  你得战斗
You have to find a way. You have to fight.
这样任何事情都永远无法束缚你  巴里
So that nothing, ever, will hold you back, Barry.
尽你所能  我知道你失去了神速
Do what you can, and I know you lost your speed,
但大家都会帮忙
but everyone's here to help.
我爸  西斯科  哈里
My dad, Cisco, Harry...
还有我
me.
快点  快点
Come on. Come on.
你换衣服还挺快
Well, you change quickly.
什么
What?
-你换掉战衣了  -对  不是  我
- Out of your suit. - Yeah, no, I--
是啊  我没了神速还穿着它感觉很奇怪
Yeah, it was, just too weird being in it without my speed.
都是你自己的错  不是吗
Well, that's your own damn fault, isn't it?
-我想是吧  -我说就是
- I guess so. - I know so.
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
我在找任何能帮我找到我女儿的东西
I'm looking for anything to help me find my daughter.
行吗
All right, just--
我丢了女儿
I don't have my daughter.
你丢了速度
You don't have your speed.
极速抓住了凯特琳
Zoom has Caitlin,
这整件事
and this whole thing--
整件事发展得越来越糟糕了
this whole thing is going to hell in a handbasket--
不  等一下  等一下
No, no, wait, wait, wait!
她的频率
Her frequency.
-什么  -杰西的频率
- What? - Jesse's frequency.
来自地球二的人  都有特定的自振频率
People from Earth-2 vibrate at a different frequency.
你也许可以通过这种方法找到她
Maybe you could track her that way.
你想办法找到斯诺吧
Figure out how to find Snow.
-你拿到了吗  -拿到了
- Did you get it? - I got it.
我们开始工作吧
Let's build this thing.
你哪都别想去  闪电侠
You're not going anywhere, Flash.
你已经得到你想要的  索罗门
You got what you want, Solomon.
这又是谁
And who is this?
另一个极速者
Another Speedster.
不  不
No, no, no!
该死
Damn it!
我就知道我们不应该这样做
I knew we shouldn't have done this.
现在我们没有办法阻止蝉了
Now we have no way to stop Cicada.
我甚至不知道我们在哪里
I mean, I don't even know when we are.
爸  爸  我们可以修好它
Dad, Dad, we can fix this.
我修不好它  诺拉
I can't fix this, Nora.
甚至连西斯科也修不好  这是威尔斯的科技
Cisco can't even fix this. This is Wells' tech.
那我们回去找威尔斯
Well, let's go back to Wells.
我们做不到  哈里的
We can't. Harry's--
哈里的大脑已经比不上从前了
Harry's mind isn't what it used to be.
不  我不是说那个威尔斯
No, I don't mean that Wells.
我是说造出粒子加速器的那个威尔斯
I mean the one that built the Particle Accelerator.
那不是威尔斯  那是艾尔伯德·斯旺
That's not Wells. That is Eobard Thawne,
逆闪
the Reverse-Flash.
我知道  他真的很聪明
I know, it's just, he's really smart.
我在想  我们能不能说服他来帮助我们
So I thought maybe we could convince him to help us.
不行  好吗  听着
No, okay, look, no.
斯旺唯一帮助过的人只有他自己
The only person Thawne ever helps is himself.
好吧
Okay.
对不起  我只是在想...
I'm sorry, I just thought that maybe--
怎么了
What?
我知道我们所在的时间了
I know when we are.
别管他  别管他
Leave him. Leave him.
我们越少干预
The less we mess--
干预时间线  我知道
Mess with the timeline. I know.
我知道这怎么回事
I know what this is.
三年前我穿越时空回到这一天
Three years ago I traveled back to this day
来寻求斯旺的帮助
to get Thawne's help.
所以你以前找过他
So you have done it before.
好吧
Well...
事情变得更加复杂了  不是吗
things just got a lot more complicated, didn't they?
巴里·艾伦
Barry Allen.
是哪个巴里·艾伦
But which Barry Allen?
明显你是
Clearly you're...
来自离现在还很遥远的未来
from a lot later than this one.
很遥远
Way later.
十分遥远
你朋友是谁
Who's your friend?
让我猜一下
Let me guess.
杰西·钱伯斯  不
Jesse Chambers. No.
应该是劳伦斯  等一下
Maybe Lawrence. Wait.
丹妮卡·威廉姆斯
Danica Williams.
她是谁并不重要
It doesn't matter who she is.
她是你的女儿
She's your daughter.
你带了女儿来见我
You've brought me your daughter.
这是
It's, um...
道恩  假如我没搞错的话
Dawn, if I'm not mistaken.
诺拉
Nora.
这很好
that's nice.
至少你还有一个女儿
At least you still have one.
诺拉  时间旅行真诡异
What, Nora, time travel's so weird.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我需要你帮我修好这个
I need you to fix this for me.
不
No...
不  假如你在这里
No, if you're here...
他也在这里
And he's here...
意味着...
that means--
你没有回家
You don't get home.
我回家了
I get home!
我回家了  我回去了
I get home. I go home!
-我拥有一切  -你回不去  斯旺
- I get everything-- - You don't go home, Thawne.
除非你帮我
Unless you help me.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
如我所说  你帮我修好它
Like I said, you're gonna fix this for me.
-修好有什么用  -吸收暗物质
- To do what? - Drain dark matter.
-谁的暗物质  -不关你的事
- Whose dark matter? - None of your business.
-关我的事  -不  不关你事
- It is my business. - No, it's not.
我不可能帮你
There's no chance that I help you--
-这不关你的事  -是蝉的
- It's none of your business-- - Cicada's!
蝉
Cicada's.
逃脱追捕的家伙
The one who got away.
你想毁掉蝉的匕首  对吧
You want to destroy Cicada's dagger, don't you?
我们想救人性命
We want to save lives.
你们想救人性命
You want to save lives.
当然了  当然了
I bet you do. I bet you do.
尤其是你自己的命  对吧  巴里·艾伦
Especially your own, right, Barry Allen?
听着  那边那个我马上就要醒来了
Look, that me, he's gonna wake up soon.
他看见我站在这里
He sees me standing here,
你的整个时间线就会灰飞烟灭
your whole timeline is gonna be blown to hell.
你就再也不可能回家了  你知道我没骗你
You're never gonna get home. You know that's true!
我知道  我知道
I know! I know!
我真是失礼
Where are my manners?
要我给你拿杯水吗
Can I get you a cup of water?
所以这是谁做的
So who made this?
一个比你聪明的人
Someone smarter than you.
我可不信
I doubt that.
艾伦  要让你的计划成功
You know, Allen, for your plan to work,
你就必须拿到
you're gonna actually gonna have to have his dagger
-他的匕首  -这个我们有办法
- in your possession-- - We've got that covered.
你们有办法  什么办法
You got that covered. How's that?
用这个
With this.
那是
Is that--
萨维塔战服上的一部分
It's a piece of Savitar's suit, yeah.
你知道你爸可笑在哪里吗  诺拉
You know what's funny about your dad, Nora,
他恨我
is he hates me.
相当恨我
Hates me with a passion,
但另一个他  这个萨维塔
and yet a version of him, this Savitar,
比我还要混蛋得多
is a much bigger jerk than I ever was.
你看见他的脸了吗  你...
Did you see the face? Did you--
看见他那张披萨一样的脸了吗
did you see the, like, pizza face.
-你能快点吗  -行  我快点
- Can you hurry up? - Yeah, I'll hurry up.
我告诉你  艾伦
I gotta tell you, Allen,
用萨维塔的战服
using Savitar's suit,
是个聪明的办法
it's a smart idea.
是她想的
It was hers.
聪明姑娘
Clever girl.
好了
Gotta go.
我期待看到这一切的结果
I still look forward to seeing how this all pans out.
诺拉
Nora.
爸爸...
Hey, Dad--
该回到一切发生的那个夜晚去了
It's time to go back to the night it all began.
走吧
Come on.
今晚就是开启未来的时刻
Tonight, the future begins.
我与我的团队在这里将要进行的工作
The work my team and I will do here
将改变当今世界对物理学的理解
will change our understanding of physics,
会给能源与医药学领域
will bring about advancements in power,
带来巨大进展
advancements in medicine,
相信我  那样的未来绝对不会太远
and trust me, that future will be here faster than you think.
我们为什么往这边走
Uh, why are we going this way?
为什么不直接用极速进入时间穹顶
Why don't we just speed into the time vault?
因为这个时刻意义非凡  诺拉
Because it's a big moment, Nora.
斯旺为了这一晚计划了14年
Thawne's been planning this night for 14 years.
如果我们用极速  他会感觉到
If we use our speed, he'll feel it.
感觉到神速力里有干扰
Feel a disturbance in the Speed Force.
最好别碰
I wouldn't do that.
[古鲁德]
威尔斯博士  粒子加速器已经准备好
Dr. Wells, the accelerator is primed
随时可以注入粒子了
and ready for particle injection.
我感觉自己应该说点意义深远的话
I feel I should say something profound like,
比如"人类迈出的一小步"什么的
"One small step for man."
发生什么了
What's happening?
威尔斯打算炸毁中城
Wells is about to blow up the city.
但我能想到的就是
All I can think of to say is
为了这一天的到来我等了数个世纪
I feel like i've waited for this day for centuries.
不再多废话了
Without further ado.
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我很好
Yeah, I'm great.
我
I'm...
凯特琳  你可以让罗尼
Caitlin, do you think you could have Ronnie
再计算一下粒子加速器参数数量吗
run the Particle Accelerator parameter numbers
再来一次就好
just one more time?
为了更精确一些
Just for good measure.
-当然  -很好
- Sure. - Great.
还有一件事  凯特琳
And, Caitlin,
我们一直留着的那瓶唐培里侬香槟
the bottle of Dom we've been saving.
就是今天吗
Is today the day?
我想也许就是今天了
I think today might be the day.
-我去把它拿过来  -很好  快点回来
- I'll go grab it. - Great, be along in a minute.
你让我们在这里坐立不安  威尔斯博士
You got us on pins and needles here, Dr. Wells.
-很激动吧  -是的
- Exciting isn't it? - Yeah.
这都要感谢团队  对吗
Well, it's all thanks to the team, right?
凯特琳  她的未婚夫罗尼  哈特利
Caitlin, fiancé Ronnie, Hartley.
哈特利做了贡献
Hartley contributed.
尤其是你  西斯科
Especially you, Cisco.
我得说我能感应到你
I have to say I have a vibe about you.
感应到你注定会成为什么样的人
About what you're destined to become.
我希望你知道  我很想加入这场冒险
I want you to know I'm very eager to be along for that adventure.
谢谢  威尔斯博士
Thank you, Dr. Wells.
这对我来说很重要
That means a great deal.
-你是  -我没有
- Oh, did you-- - I didn't.
我们还是去打开加速器再开一瓶香槟吧
Shall we just go turn on an accelerator and pop some champagne?
-我觉得  -很好
- I think-- - Okay.
他走了
He's gone.
晚上好  巴里·艾伦
Good evening, Barry Allen.
我没想到这么快就见到你
I was not expecting you this soon.
她认识你吗
She knows you?
我还认识你  诺拉·韦斯特艾伦
I know you as well, Nora West-Allen.
也被称作XS
Also known as XS.
重启军团的第五名成员
Fifth recruit in the rebooted Legion of--
吉迪恩  粒子加速器即将爆炸
Gideon, the particle accelerator is about to explode.
我需要你重新调试系统的链式反应
I need you to recalibrate the system's chain reaction
把一些暗物质放回到这个瓶子里
so some of the dark matter is repositioned into this vial,
并且不要记录相关报告
and record no reports of this...
诺拉
Nora!
你真的恨他  是吗
You really hate him, don't you?
你不知道他做了什么吗
Do you not know what he did?
我知道他是你的死敌
I know he was your archenemy.
他杀死了我母亲
He killed my mother...
毁掉了我们的家
and our home
当时我才11岁
when I was 11 years old.
一个11岁的小孩子
An 11-year-old boy.
你知道他为什么这样做吗
You know why he did it?
他认为如果我遭受的痛苦足够恐怖的话
He thought if I suffered a tragedy that was horrific enough,
我就永远不会恢复
I'd never recover
也就永远不会成为闪电侠
and never become The Flash.
我不知道这些
I-- I didn't know that.
也许很多在我身上发生的事
There's probably a lot that's happened to me
都没有在闪电侠博物馆里展览
that's not in The Flash museum.
这就是为什么你不想让我和你一起来  是吗
It's why you didn't want me to come with you, isn't it?
不是因为危险
It's not because it was dangerous,
或是时间线
or because of the timeline,
而是因为你不想让我知道
but because you didn't want me
你身上发生的这些可怕的事
to know these awful things about you
这样等我回去以后  就不会对这些印象深刻
so it's not what I would remember most when I went back.
你不必保护我免受这些伤痛
You don't have to protect me from this stuff.
-我需要  -不  你不必
- Yes, I do. - No, you don't.
不  我真的需要
Yes, yes, I do.
你是我的女儿
You're my daughter.
而你是我的父亲
Yeah, and you're my father,
我只是想了解我的父亲
and I just want to know my father.
重新校准完毕
Recalibration complete.
要来了
Here we go.
暗物质取回成功
Dark matter retrieval successful.
该让时间恢复正常了
Let's go get our time back in place.
[急诊]
脊髓创伤
Spinal cord trauma,
他的下腹以下都没有知觉了
he's lost all feeling to his lower quadrants.
那是哈里森·威尔斯
That's Harrison Wells.
威尔斯博士  我要你抓紧我的手
Dr. Wells, I need you to squeeze my hand.
这是个好兆头
That's a good sign.
二十四岁男性  被闪电击中
24-year-old male, struck by lightning.
得找个全面的创伤专家小组
I need a full trauma panel.
送他到一号诊室
Get him to bay one.
这座城市是怎么了
What is happening to this city?
格蕾丝的病房在四楼
Grace's room is on the fourth floor.
应该没问题
This should work.
就放在这里
Let's put it right here.
成功了
We did it.
走吧
Come on.
你们真的去了吗
Did you even go?
都说了时间旅行很诡异
Told you time travel was weird.
-都办成了吗  -对
- Everything worked? - Yeah.
德怀尔还在医院吗
Is Dwyer still at the hospital?
一直陪着她
Hasn't left her side.
你们部署好发射器了吗
Did you plant the transmitter?
一切就绪
Yeah, we sure did.
一起去捉蝉吧
Let's go get Cicada.
准备好了吗  巴里
You ready, Barry?
就位
I'm ready.
蝉
Cicada.
你就是这么称呼我的吗
Is that what you call me?
不是所有超能力者
Not all meta-humans
都要对格蕾丝的遭遇负责
are responsible for what happened to Grace.
不  他们都要
Yes, they are.
他们造成的破坏  死亡
The destruction they cause, the death,
伤痛
the pain.
我了解伤痛和死亡
I know about pain and death.
报复整个世界
Taking it out on the world,
是不会有帮助的  想想格蕾丝
that's not gonna help. Think about Grace.
我无时无刻不在想着她  闪电侠
She's all I think about, Flash.
我在为她创造更安宁的世界
And I'm making the world safe for her.
每一个超能力者都得死
Every meta-human must go.
那你呢
Then what about you?
你现在也是超能力者了
You're a meta-human now.
没错
I am,
在灭了你们后  我会自行了断
and after you're gone, I'll join you.
一共四人
All four of you.
拜托了  要管用啊
Come on, work.
-起作用了  -成功了
- It worked. - It worked.
尝尝这个
Let's see how you like it.
西斯科  快
Cisco, now.
把它传送走
Breach it out of here!
你完了
Gotcha.
老兄
Oh, man.
你看起来不太妙啊
You look like you're having a day.
是因为我刚把你的匕首扔进了外太空
Is it 'cause I just threw your dagger into outer space,
还是因为你才发现你没有干掉我
or 'cause you're just now realizing you didn't kill me.
你输了
We stopped you.
别高兴得太早
You stop nothing.
卫星追踪到那枚匕首
The satellite's tracking the dagger
正穿过外大气层返回
back through the exosphere.
各位  蝉正在召回太空中的匕首
Guys, Cicada's recalling the dagger back from space.
快快快
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
受死吧
This ends now.
巴里
Barry!
不
No!
我们跳舞吧  板球怪人
Let's dance, cricket freak.
面部识别没有检测到德怀尔
Dwyer's not popping up in facial recognition.
他的匕首上的暗物质没有追踪到
And there's no dark matter traces from his dagger.
他不会离开他的外甥女太久的
Well, he won't stay away from his niece for long,
等他回来时  我们就准备好了
and when he returns, we'll be ready.
没错  多亏了冰霜杀手
Yeah, we will, thanks to Killer Frost.
我不明白
I don't understand.
她怎么还能出来
How can she still come out?
她不是来自于暗物质
She didn't come from dark matter,
所以我猜她不受蝉的暗物质影响
so I guess she's immune to Cicada's dagger.
她可能是从根本上阻止蝉的关键
She just might be the key to stopping Cicada for good.
或许我们应该和她聊下
Maybe we should go check in with her.
-你觉得如何  -好
- What do you think? - Yeah.
-板球怪人  -是的
- Cricket freak, huh? - Yeah.
就那么脱口而出了
Just came out.
为你骄傲
Proud of you.
-夏烙克  -歇洛克
- Hey, "Sher-loke." - Sherloque.
-喝茶吗  -不  谢谢
- Tea? - No, thank you.
你看到我的...
Have you see my--
-日记吗  -是的
- journal. - Yeah.
请原谅我  但我忍不住注意到了
Forgive me, but couldn't help but notice
这部作品
this composition.
真的没什么特别的
That's really nothing special.
但它
But it...
感觉很特别
feels like something special.
我不想吹嘘  但我会好多种语言
I don't like to brag, but speak a lot of languages
不过这种语言
and yet this one...
我不认识
this one I don't recognize.
这是一种时间语言
It's a time language.
时间语言  真的吗
Time language, really?
用来记录事件
It's used to record events
可以忽略时间线的改变
regardless of changes in the timeline
所以不管发生了什么  我都会记得我爸
so no matter what happens I'll always remember my dad.
这种语言要从哪学习呢
Hmm, where does one learn something like that?
时间旅行学校吗
Time travel school?
事实上  是我发明的
I created it, actually.
你发明的
You created it?
聪明的姑娘
Clever girl.
对不起
I forget myself.
这是你的
This is yours.
翻译结果
时间线是可改变的
他们是最棒的
They were the best.
爸爸
Dad.
-爸  我不  -没关系
- Dad, I didn't-- - It's all right.
我理解
I understand.
-我爱你  -我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you, too.
你有想过
Do you ever think about stopping
阻止即将发生的事情吗
what's about to happen?
每天都想
Every day.
谢谢你今天带着我
Thanks for bringing me with you today.
这对我意义重大
It meant a lot.
我很高兴你来了
I'm glad you came.
老爸  来啊
Hey, Old Man, come on.
来啊
Come on.
老爸
Old Man?
晚上好  诺拉·韦斯特艾伦
Good evening, Nora West-Allen.
吉迪恩  再次输入数据
Gideon, another data entry.
上传完成并保存
Entry uploaded and recorded.
要把它发给同一个接受者吗
Shall I send it to the same recipient?
是的
Yes.
发送成功
Entry sent.
你还需其他帮助吗
Would you like assistance with anything else?
帮我发一条私人短信
Yes, send a personal message from me.
你要发什么
What would you like it to say?
我还是自己来发吧
Actually, I'll deliver it myself.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
好的  诺拉
Yes, Nora.
没错  我们需要
Yes, we do.
90号地球
你失败了
You failed.
你为什么要这样做
Why are you doing this?
这是你自作自受
You did this to yourself,
而今天  所有人都将毁灭
and now, all of you will perish.